(内华达州 1889年)
这里都是软泥 好好的挖吧
Awful soft dirt in here. Make sure you shore it up good.
里面要闷死人了
It's like working inside a cow down here.
挖到宝了 这足以买下农场了
Una vaca plata that is going to pay off my ranch.
还买农场呢
Your ranch.
这就像找女人一样
You know, it's like a woman.
叫你难以自拔
It's all you ever talk about.
然后她就可以大捞特捞
Meanwhile, she's taking all your money.
但你把钱全花在酒上面了
And you, you spend all of your money on whiskey.
你很快就会知道了
But you're going to miss me soon.
维多？
Victor?
- 维多？- 啊
- Victor? - Ugh!
维多？
Victor?
杰夫
Jefe. Jefe!
杰夫 维多走了
Jefe, Victor is gone.
什么？走了
What do you mean, "gone"?
我们才刚开始呢
We were working the face.
他不可能超过我的
I know he couldn't have got past me.
但他就是不见了
But now he's just gone.
杰夫
Jefe! Jefe!
糟糕
Damn it!
胡安 你在哪里？
Juan! Where are ya?
《异形魔怪4》
(摒弃镇)
(老张的店)
很多人都要走了
So many people leaving.
大家都要摒弃我们吗？
Is everyone rejecting us?
不是的 福元
No, Fu Yien, we're sure.
他们要走是因为矿坑关闭了
They are leaving because the mine is closed.
看来这里得改个名字
Maybe we need a different name.
可能这名字不太好
Perhaps it was not the best choice, huh?
不一定吧
Maybe not.
儿子啊
Son.
胡安
Juan Padilla,
你看着这帽子个把月了 到底要不要买？
you've been looking at that hat for a month. Buy it or don't buy it.
不行 我买不起
No, no, I can't afford it.
先欠着 以后再付
You take it on credit, pay us later.
不准赊帐
No credit!
史丹要走了 他正在搬东西上车
Stan Kelton is leaving. Loading up his wagon.
史丹也要走？那镇上不就没有铁匠了
Stan, too? Now we're a town without a blacksmith.
最后这里会唱空城记
It'll end up as a ghost town
除非矿坑再开放
if that mine doesn't re-open.
要是大伙都走光了 谁还会要来买东西呢？
If everybody leaves, who will buy our things?
鬼才会来
No one.
所以我们该回老家去了
And we'll go back to China.
要回老家
Only way you going back to China
你得先学会游泳
is if you learn how to swim.
抽到什么签？
What does I Ching say?
"强大的征服者即将来到"
"Expect arrival of great conqueror."
矿坑不会永远关闭着的
The mine will not stay closed.
里面的银矿价值连城呢
That ore is turning out 100 ounces to the ton.
比价值连城更多
Two hundred, my friend.
还更多吗？谁都不会让这种财富溜走的
Two hundred? Well, nobody is walking away from riches like that.
谁都不会的
Nobody!
要是你也看到我所见到的 你也照样要落跑的
Well, if you saw what I saw, you might walk away.
你根本没说过你见到什么
You never really told us what you saw.
根本就没看到
I saw nothing,
但是看不到比看到是什么 还要更可怕
but the "nothing," it was worse than anything I have ever seen.
难道你也想打退堂鼓了？
You're not thinking of pulling out, too?
不 才不可能
No, I cannot do that.
否则我就像你一贫如洗了
I would lose everything, like you.
大家都一样
Like all of us.
听着 是有关矿坑的事
Listen! It's about the mine.
矿坑的老板就要来了
The owner of the mine is coming.
他要从费城过来
All the way from Philadelphia.
他说"不能接受 矿坑的利润变少"
He say, "Low profit from mine unacceptable.
"全力出动"
"Proceeding with all dispatch.
"我们要亲自处理此事"
"Will take matters into hand personally."
署名 甘哈兰
Sign, Hiram Gummer.
这名字可真响亮
That's a real $2 name.
我打赌他会快刀斩乱麻
I'll wager he gets this thing solved
要不然就要火烧屁股了
faster than a bee with a horse on its tail.
跟你打赌
Bet you!
回见
Yeah, see you later now!
有马车来了
The stage is coming! It's coming!
迪科帕 克莉斯丁 有马车 要过来了
Tecopa, Ms. Christine, the stage! It's coming!
- 你们猜他长什么样子 - 可能很胖
- What do you think he looks like? - He's probably fat.
有钱人一向都很胖的
Rich people are always fat.
噢 天哪
Oh, my word.
- 里面有人吗？- 满满的都是行李
- Anybody in there? - It's full of luggage.
- 是时候了 - 的确是
- It's about time. - Indeed it is.
- 您说什么？- 让我上去
- Pardon me, ma'am. - Let me in there.
我等不及要离开这里
Can't wait to get out of this place.
怎么没有人下来
No one got out.
甘先生吗？
Mr. Hiram Gummer?
就是我
I am he.
我是张彭连 叫我老张就好
I am Pyong Chang.
这是我的店铺
This is my market.
- 你并不胖嘛 - 闭嘴
- You're not very fat. - Quiet.
你一定有钱的要死
You must have enough money to burn a wet mule, huh?
我叫克莉斯丁
Mr. Gummer, I'm Christine Lord.
我是旅馆的主人
Proprietress of the local hotel.
你真是美丽大方
Well, you're lovelier than Fifth Avenue in Spring.
欢迎到摒弃镇
Welcome to Rejection.
这名字真是贴切
Aptly named, it would seem.
我是来找安德鲁贝克威的
I'm here to see one Andrew Beckwith,
我写给他三封信都没有回音
to whom I've sent three communiques, all unanswered.
我要马上和他讲话
I want to speak to him forthwith.
这件事不好办
That might prove to be a little difficult.
为什么？他在哪里？
Why? Where is he?
在那上面 最后一批要走的人
On that. The last stage out of here.
什么？
What?
真是太妙了 最后一批吗？
That's just dandy. The last?
乘客太少了
Too few passengers.
矿坑几星期前关闭了
You see, the mine closed several weeks ago.
所以你才会来 对不对？
That is why you're here, isn't it?
矿坑关闭了？
Closed? The mine closed?
这么重要的事我一点都不知情
I feel I've not been privy to critical, most needful information.
你不知道 里面出了什么事吗？
You don't know what happens at the mine?
一天就死了17个矿工
Seventeen miners were killed in one day.
其他工人都不敢去了
The workers abandoned it
出了什么事呢？
Seventeen? What on earth happened?
谁也不清楚
No one knows.
你们要我猜谜吗？
Must you speak in riddles?
只有胡安看见
The only person who could answer that question is Juan Pedilla.
那就叫他马上来见我
Then I should like to speak with him straight away.
他出去了
Well, he's out riding his land.
应该很快就回来了
We expect him back shortly.
你一定累了
Please, you must be tired from your traveling.
我带你到旅馆去
Won't you let me show you to the hotel?
很好
Oh, very well.
来 我需要有人帮忙搬东西
Come, come. I'll need assistance with my kit.
这是银行 不过当然是关闭着
This is our bank. Closed, of course.
铁匠在这里 也关门了
Our blacksmith, also closed.
这里是邮局 也关了
And our post office. Closed.
好不热闹的地方
Of course. Quite the bustling metropolis.
"强大的征服者"
"Great conqueror."
这就是我的旅馆 欢迎光临
And this is my hotel, welcome.
走这边
Right this way.
嗯
Hmm...
好一堆武器 你是收藏吗？
An impressive arsenal. Are you a collector?
矿工是来西部发财的
The miners came West to strike it rich.
每当他们该结帐时
When it came time to settle their bills,
大多都只剩下身上的枪了
many of them had only their firearms left.
现在我采用每日付费制
Now I collect payments daily.
怎么可以 先记帐就好了
Nonsense. Just keep a running tab.
你的人真无礼
Your man is rather impudent.
迪科帕不是我的人 只是朋友
Tecopa is not my man. He is my friend.
这只是帐棚而已
But this is a tent.
你真敏锐 喜欢哪一个？
Yes. You're quite observant. Which one would you like?
就这个吧
This one right here.
很好 午餐几时会好？
Dandy. And what time will luncheon be served?
煤矿关闭后
Well, since the mine has closed,
补给车就不来了
the supply wagons have stopped,
所以餐点会比较有限
so our menu's a bit limited.
我可以帮你烧一碗豆子
I could fix you a pot of beans.
不必了 你应该有面粉
Nonsense. Surely you have flour,
糖浆和红姜吧
molasses and ginger.
我想吃姜饼 对 那样子就很好
I should like a ginger bread cake. Yes, that should do nicely.
要我把他勒死吗？
Do you want me to strangle him?
不 我们需要他
No. We need him.
动人的音乐加上可口的一餐
Delightful music and a passable meal,
要是再有一杯美酒更好
which I should like to end with an aperitif.
那可不是吗？
Wouldn't we all?
最后一块姜饼 你要吃吗？
Fu Yien, would you like that last piece of gingerbread?
要
Yes.
那就去我的蓝色袋子里
Then go to my small carpet bag, the blue one,
拿我的白兰地过来 好的 先生
and fetch my bottle of peach brandy. Yes, sir.
姜饼怎么没了？
What happened to the ginger bread?
当然是我吃掉了
I ate it, of course.
可是你说…
But I thought you said I could have...
给你个建议 年轻人
A word of advice, young man.
谁都会被人占便宜 要是你占得了便宜 尽管去做
Anyone can be taken advantage of, and if you can, do.
这样教小孩子很糟糕
That is terrible advice to give a child.
他得面对这世界的现实
Someone needs to teach the boy the ways of the world.
他当然会很清楚这些的
I assure you, he knows them.
- 胡安来了 他刚到店里 - 胡安？
- Juan's here. He's over at the store. - "Juan"?
胡安 他是矿工
Juan Pedilla. The miner.
噢 是的
Oh, yes, yes.
不 矿并没有被挖光 还有很多
No, no, no, no. The mine is not played out. Not at all.
里面还有很多的银矿
There is plenty more silver in there.
只是没人敢进去开采
It's just no one wants to go in and get it.
出了事以后还有七个人进去过 却没有一个回来
Seven more men go up since accident. None come back.
我的祖先曾经说过 山里面有兽精
My ancestors talked of spirit beasts that live inside those mountains.
"兽精"？
"Spirit beasts"?
怪兽就住在地底
Beasts from the underworld.
无视一切 只会杀戮
Blind to all, but killing.
你们都知道 自己在说些什么吗？
Have you all taken leave of your senses?
召集剩下的矿工
Juan, I want you to gather up the remaining miners.
把那鬼东西给我捉住
Hunt down whatever is doing this.
然后杀个精光
And fill 'em full of more holes
片甲不留
than a cabbage leaf in a hail storm.
- 就是这样 - 甘先生
- Precisely. - Senor Gummer,
城北还有一些矿工
there are some miners still camped north of town.
我可以找他们来
Now, I can go and talk to them,
但是没有钱他们可不做事
but they are not going to go back there unless you pay them.
可能要用双倍的工钱
Maybe even double wages.
付钱？想再找回工作吗？
Pay them? To earn their own jobs back?
告诉你 他们都很害怕
Senor, I'm just telling you, they are scared.
好吧
Very well.
不过为了防止
To ensure that my resources are not being squandered
被这群恶棍乱敲竹杠 我和你一起去
by this cabal of hooligans, I shall accompany you myself.
明天一早
First thing in the morning.
这就对了
Now you're talking.
你带了哪种枪？
What kind of gun did you bring, eh?
一定很炫很新型吧
Bet you it's big and fancy.
我没有带枪
I don't own a firearm.
怎么？
Yes?
这地方是大西部
This is the Wild West, Mr. Gummer.
你没看过小说吗？
You don't read the dime novels?
要是碰上坏人 你可得保卫自己
You see a bad guy, you gotta smoke 'em up.
先生 马准备好了
Senor Gummer, your horse is ready.
先生
SenorGummer.
早安
Good morning.
骑车很辛苦
Uh,senor it is a hard day's ride
尤其在这片荒野中
over very rough country.
这是越野型的 让马背着工具
Well, this is the cross-country model. The horse can carry my kit.
我们走吧
Off we go!
真是糟糕的路
Deplorable road conditions.
嗯
Uh.
不 我想我需要…
No, no, I'd like some, uh... Oh.
可能只要… 谢谢 很好
Maybe just... Thank you. Ah, very good.
我再没有骑过马
Yeah, I haven't been on a horse since I...
自从六岁生日后
Since my sixth birthday party.
不对 那时骑的是匹骆驼
No, actually, that was a camel.
噢 唔
Oh, Whoa.
- 甘先生 - 怎么了？
- Mr. Gummer! - Yes?
这是给你的
This is for you. Oh, I beg your pardon.
到了大西部 带着武器比较好
This is the Wild West. Never go unarmed.
真的不必了
Well, no, indeed.
谢谢你 小子
Thank you, son, thank you.
你看他真的会是那个 强大的征服者吗？
You really think he is a great conqueror?
要是他骑骆驼比骑马 还要厉害的话
Only if he can ride a camel better than he can ride a horse.
先别妄下判断
Let's not judge yet, Tecopa.
他是我们唯一的希望了
He's the only chance we have. Hmm.
各位 大家好
Howdy, gents.
就这些人吗？
This is our army?
只有他们肯去
These are the only ones willing to go.
总比没有好 不必花钱给胆小鬼
All the better. No need to waste my money on cowards.
各位 就是这位主顾 甘哈兰先生
Men, this is the patrén, Mr. Hiram Gummer.
他们是华特兄弟
These are the Walter brothers,
- 叫做砖头和石头 - 嗯
- Brick and Stony. - Uh-huh.
- 这是强生大马 - 强生先生
- This is Big Horse Johnson. - Mr. Johnson.
他是索基
And this is Soggy.
索基
Soggy.
很好
Indeed.
(最后一文矿坑)
你们进去吧
Well, in you go.
然后呢？
And what?
然后给我回报
And report back to me.
好吧
Oh, very well.
你们都没有足够的领导力
As none of you possess sufficient leadership skills,
我得自己来带头
I shall supervise the endeavor myself.
胡安
Juan.
出发
Vémonos.
- 等一下 - 是杰夫 他是工头
- Wait. - Ah, that was Jefe. Our foreman.
我的帽子
My hat.
拿去吧
Here.
他不需要了
He ain't gonna need it.
戴戴看
Try it on.
谢谢
Thank you, Jefe.
天啊
Oh, my...
矿坑就到这里了 维多曾到过这里
This is the end of the mine, where Victor was.
我们还活着
Well, we're still alive.
攻击过你们的东西 好像已经不在了
Whatever attacked you, it would seem to be gone.
我宣布矿坑现在已经安全了
Gentlemen, I declare this mine perfectly safe.
- 说得没有错 - 里面连个鬼影都没有
- Dang right. - Ain't nothingin there but ghosts.
你根本不必付钱给他们
You don't need to pay them no wages.
希望我们是对的
I pray that we are correct.
太阳要下山了 就在这里扎营好了
Well, sun's gettinglow. Might as well set up camp.
这里不能扎营的
We can't camp here.
要找有树木的地方
I need trees.
这样睡比较好
It's better for the posture.
天哪 你又在欺负 那东西了吗？
Oh, damn. You gonna start torturing that thing?
这样我会比较好睡
Helps me sleep.
而且马也喜欢听
And the horses like it, too.
那就去弹给他们听吧
Well, go play it for them.
你不懂音乐不能怪我
Ain't my fault you lack a musical ear.
你想要多快重开矿坑？
How soon do you think you can re-open the mine?
十万火急
Post haste.
越快越好
The sooner the better.
很好
Good.
因为我得持续工作 才能保住我的农场
Because I need to keep working if I don't want to lose my ranch.
我以为你也是个矿工
I thought you were a miner.
我是矿工
Well, I am a miner,
但是我父亲 一直梦想要买下一个农场
but my father always dreamed of having a ranch for us one day.
后来呢？
And?
有一次矿坑塌陷他死掉了 那时我还小
He was killed in a cave-in when I was a boy.
我的母亲 带着我们 一个个矿坑去工作
Uh, my mother, she moved us from mining camp to mining camp.
因为那里需要女人
They always need a woman
来洗衣烧饭
to do the laundry and the cooking.
我的厨子离开好几星期了
I've been without my cook for weeks.
你总是什么都有 对不对？
You always had everything, didn't you?
丰衣足食
Several of everything.
我要的不多
I'd just like to get one of something.
搞什么鬼？
What on earth?
可恶 马跑了怎么回去呀
Oh, damn, we'll be hours finding them horses.
你这混蛋
Soggy, you sorry sack!
我要把你打扁
I'm gonna pound you blue!
大家不要急
Easy, easy, everybody.
打他 砖头
You pound him, Brick!
他最会放臭屁了
He's always fartingaround.
你上哪去了？
Where the hell are you?
躲起来对你没好处的
It won't do you no good hidin'!
听声音
Céllate
听到没有？
Do you hear that?
我越找你会越生气
Soggy, the longer I'm lookin', the madder I get!
- 老天 什么鬼东西？- 该死的
- Good Lord, what? - Tarnation!
砖头 你还好吗？
Brick! You all right?
石头 不要乱打瞎打的
Stony! Don't you go shooting blind out there!
砖头
Brick!
他在哪里？
Well, where is he?
不知道 他不在那里
Don't know! He ain't out there!
那会是谁？
Who's that?
谁在那里？我们手上有枪喔
Who's over there? We've got guns over here.
是什么鬼东西？
What... What... What in God's name?
开枪开快一点 全部杀光
You gotta shoot faster! Kill it, man!
- 我们得找个高的地方 - 哪里？
- We've got to get up somewhere! - Where?
到那大石头上
Over on that rock!
快到石头上面来
Senor Gummer! Over here on the rock! On the rock!
大马 在这里 不要站在地面上
Big Horse! Over here! You gotta get off the ground!
大马 来这里
Big Horse! Here!
不要 开枪没有用
No! Big Horse, you can't shoot it!
到这边 快点
This way, man! Quickly!
到石头上面来
Get on the rock!
老天哪
Good heaven.
真是臭死人了
What a dreadful odor.
在矿坑里面 也有闻到这种味道 就是它们
I smelled it in the mine, it was them.
它们是从软泥冲上来的
They came up through the soft dirt.
但是它们无法穿过石头
At least it can't penetrate rock.
它没有眼睛
It has no eyes.
那它们 怎么知道我们的位置？
How did they find us?
靠声音
It's the sound.
只要我们发出声音 就会被发现 烧水声音也是一样
Every time we made a sound, even your teapot.
那就是它们狩猎的方式
That's how they hunt.
我们不能老待在这里吧
We can't just stay here.
那些小路上面铺着石块
These foothills are made of rock.
我们可以一路走回镇上去
We can walk on them almost all the way back to Rejection.
走路？
Walk?
难不成你想飞回去
Well, unless you can fly.
你在做什么？
Tecopa. What are you doing?
- 挖个洞插旗子 - 插旗子？
- Digginga spot for a flagpole. - A flagpole?
这种时候你管他 内华达州有没有插旗子吗？
Does it concern you that Nevada hasn't yet adopted a flag?
这很重要 我马上就好
We will one day, and I'll be ready.
他们回来了 是胡安和甘先生 他们回来了
They're back! They're back! It's Juan and Mr. Gummer! They're back!
要是我就跑得越远越好
I'd have walked twice that far to get away.
这种怪物真是太恐怖了
Those are the most savagerous beasts I've ever seen!
难道你没有开枪扫射
Well, didn't you let loose?
大开杀戒吗？
Let fly? Barrels blazing?
老费迪 你不懂
Old Fred, you don't understand.
它们不在地底下的话 它们就用飞的
When they're not underground, they're flying.
飞得很快
Very fast.
龙 是土龙
Tu-Long. Dragons. Dirt dragons.
在中国没见过这种东西
We never had them in China.
大马和胡安对怪物开枪 但是杀不死它们
Big Horse, Juan, they tried to shoot them, but couldn't.
除非你是个快速神枪手
You'd have to be an unparalleled shootist.
可是等一下 就是这个
But wait, that's it.
我们得发出电报
A telegram, we must send a telegram immediately.
让我来 我会
Let me do it. I know how.
这样 "征求枪手"
Here. "Wanted. Gun fighter.
"内华达州摒弃镇"
"Town of Rejection, Nevada,
"需要经验丰富的快枪手"
"seeks experienced, quick-draw artist,"
"必须处变不惊"
"calm in face of dangenr."
"价码面议"
"Salary, negotiable."
发到各大地区
Now, send that to the Territorial Enterprise,
邮局 还有威其塔电讯去
the Denver Post and the Wichita Eagle.
你要雇用枪手吗？
You're going to hire a gunfighter?
我认为这是个好主意
Bien, bien, bien. I think that is a good idea.
这样子好吗？这些枪手老是
But is it wise? A gunfighter's usually mean, wild.
酗酒成性 胡作非为
Drink, shoot inside house.
我们需要这种视死如归的人
But we need someone with fortitude.
要能够出生入死的勇猛铁汉
Someone with a little sand in their craw.
正是 要具有精湛的枪法…
Exactly. Someone who is proficient with firearms, who can...
百步之内仍旧 百发百中的神枪手
Shoot the nuts off a squirrel at 100 paces.
- 谢谢 - 就像霍立德那样的神枪手
- Thank you. - Someone like Doc Holiday.
但不是早死了的枪手
Except one that ain't dead.
霍立德死了吗？
Doc Holiday's dead?
弄好了
Okay! It's done!
我们就等消息吧
Now, we wait.
很不错吧 对不？
Handsome, no?
的确是
Oh, very.
这是我
It's me.
能够有自己雕像的人可不多
Very few men have statues of themselves.
是印地安人吗？
A cigar store Indian?
有个推销员给了我这个
Oh, a salesman gave that to me
他当时付不了帐
when he couldn't pay his bill.
那可能是我
Well, it could be me.
你的轮胎修好了
Mr. Gummer, I fixed your wheel.
不可能 轮胎破得不像样
Impossible, it's a complete loss.
不会的
Nope.
我的… 真是…
Well, my, my, that's...
太棒了 真是感谢你呀
Remarkable. Thank you. Thank you very much.
请付五块钱就好
That will be $5, please.
少来了
Five? Now listen here.
修个轮胎 不要两块钱
No workman would dare ask more than two bits.
我是镇上唯一会修轮胎的
I'm the only wheel-fixer in town.
不然你得上卡森城去找人修
No one else 'til Carson City.
这简直是趁火打劫嘛
But that's highway robbery.
给你个建议
A word of advice, Mr. Gummer.
谁都会被人占便宜 要是你占得了便宜 尽管去做
Anyone can be taken advantage of. And if you can, do.
福元
Fu Yien,
我身上的钱不够 我用东西跟你换吧
I'm a trifle short of cash at present. May we barter instead?
我把这部单车给你 当作我付的钱吧
For services rendered, you may have the bicycle.
我已经越来越会骑马了
It's yours. I'm becoming quite the expert horseman.
好耶
Dandy, Mr. Gummer!
上去吧
There you go.
不是 这样 我把你稳住 保持平衡
No. Ok, here, here, here. I'll steady you. Now, get your balance.
我一推你就踩踏板 前轮要保持直行
Now, when I push, press the pedals and keep the front wheel straight.
好了吗？开始走了
Ready? Off you go.
还不赖嘛
Not bad!
真是不赖
Not bad at all.
(一个月后)
这到底还要吵多久？
How long is this bedlam to last?
还要几天 我们要把井挖深一点
Oh, a few more days. We're deepening our well.
我们对这引擎很自豪
You know, we're quite proud of our engine.
很快就可以用来发电点灯了
It's going to run our electric lights for us one day.
那你要能够忍受那鬼声音
If you can abide the racket.
要是你一起帮忙我们会更快
Well, the work would go faster if you'd help.
我这样的人 是不做劳力工作的
A man of my means doesn't engage in physical labor.
所以我们这么做
Which brings us
才可以向你收钱
to your bill.
你不是有记帐吗？
You're running a tab.
那我没有同意过
In point of fact, I didn't agree to that.
好小姐 我到了哪里 亮出名字人人都买我的帐
Mrs. Lord, in any civilized place, my name alone is, quite sufficient.
但是在这种荒野西部 我们都只用现金交易
Well, out here in the rough and tumble West, we tend to use cash.
你手上的金表带 应该值20块钱吧
Now, that is a $20 gold piece on your watch fob, isn't it?
那表当然也是金子做的吧
And the watch itself is gold, of course?
还有袖扣呢？是钻石吧？
And the cufflinks? Genuine diamonds?
难道你要我像路边小贩一样
Are you proposing that I barter with you,
用这些来和你交换吗？少来这套了
as I would some street vendor in Calcutta? Don't be absurd.
你先给我记帐
You will run a proper tab until this,
直到这鬼地方的银行开了
pathetic town has a proper bank
我的钱就可以汇到了
to which I can wire funds.
好了 这是怎么回事？
Here now. What is going on?
你怎么不骑车上？
Why aren't you riding that wheel?
没时闲 我很忙
No time. I'm working.
你们这些人最会拖延时闻
You men, you'll take forever.
你们要小孩做大人的事吗？
Using a boy to do a man's work.
这下面很窄的
Very narrow down there.
只有他的身材 挤得进去
He's the only one small enough to widen it.
好吧…
Well...
等他把洞挖大了
Well, the moment it is wide enough,
你就得找人下去换手
I expect to see one of you down there in his place.
让他可以去骑车
And he back on that bicycle.
其实我应该要道歉
Uh, Mrs. Lord, I should like to apologize.
事实上
The truth is
我的金币 手表和袖扣 是我最后剩下的财产
my coin, watch and cufflinks are all I own in the world.
你说什么？
I beg your pardon?
我父亲最后老得痴呆
My father, in his final demented days,
把他所有的财产资金 通通投资
sold all his holdings and invested everything, the entire family fortune,
到某一个银矿中
in a certain silver mine.
我明白了
I see.
之前我很无礼 很抱歉
I was rude earlier. I apologize.
只要银矿开工了
Once I get the mine running,
我就可以还你钱 而且我会马上离开
I'll pay my bill in full and be on the first stage out of here.
就像老费迪讲的 屋漏偏逢连夜雨
As old Fred would say, that's a real gully washer.
别看我 这和我没关系
Don't look at me. I had nothing to do with it.
希望老费迪在这之前 就到达驿站了
I hope Old Fred made it to the muling station before this hit.
昨天那么热 今天却下雨了
Yesterday a desert. Today a monsoon.
只要矿坑重开了
Once I re-open the mine,
整个镇就会繁荣
the whole town will prosper.
你就会要什么有什么
You'll be able to afford whatever your hearts desire.
那你想要什么呢？
And what is it that your heart desires, Mr. Gummer?
回到过去的生活
To return to the life I had.
每天早上醒来就想到
To wake up every morning and wonder,
"今天我要怎么花钱呢？"
"What will I spend my money on today?"
说真的
A curious philosophy.
我打赌你怎么花钱不重要
I would venture that it matters not how you spend your money,
重要的是你怎么运用生命
but how you spend your life.
甘先生
Mr. Gummer.
大人讲话不要插嘴
Don't interrupt your elders.
没关系 好小姐
Never you mind, Mrs. Lord.
等到死神来敲我的门 我会改邪归正的
I'll amend my misspent life when the Grim Reaper comes calling.
我建议你把枪收好
I recommend that you keep that hog leg skinned.
除非你想自找麻烦
Unless you got a desire to bejumpingover hot coals in hell.
请问你是谁？先生
And who might you be, sir?
凯力
Kelly.
黑手凯力吗？
Black Hand Kelly?
我要找甘哈兰
I'm looking for Hiram Gummer.
我就是
That would be me.
你是不是登了个启事？
You posted yourself an advertisement?
是的
I did. Yes, I did.
你要我杀谁？
So, who do you want me to kill?
- 那边那个瘪三吗？- 不是
- That Injun over there - No, no, no no, no.
要杀的不是人 是怪物
It's not so much a "who" as a "what."
它们会从地底窜出来
They spring from the ground like...
就像怪物一样
Like some demonic trout.
我们叫它土龙
We call them Tu-Long. Uh, Dirt Dragons.
这东西味道一定很烈
This stuff sure must be a whole lot stronger than it tastes.
你一定会觉得那是天方夜谭
We're well aware that it sounds fantastic,
但我们说的都是真的
but we can assure you it's all quite true.
它们很凶残 动作很快
They're ferocious and fast.
要真的勇士才能打倒它
It takes some real backbone to face them down.
我只会为了取乐 去打响尾蛇
Amigo, I like to fight with rattle snakes just for the fun of it,
我会先引他咬我的靴子
and I give them the first bite to boot.
先别自吹自擂 你很会用枪吗？
Hyperbole aside, you are accurate with a firearm?
怀疑我的能力吗？先生
You questioning my abilities, sir?
- 我是生意人 所以我… - 嘿 小子
- As an astute business man, I'm simply... - Hey, boy!
给我丢个苹果过来这里
Toss me one of them apples over here.
看吧 我就说 要闹事了
See, I knew it. Shoot inside house.
要丢很高吗？
Throw it high?
不用 直接对着我丢过来
No,no,no. You throw it right straight at me.
准备好了吗？
Okay, you ready?
好了
Anytime.
怎么？
What?
你不是要射苹果的吗？
We thought you'd shoot apple. Yeah.
我们以为你是要示范…
Obviously, we are expecting to see a demonstration of...
你获雇用了
You're hired.
在中国 没人会对着墙开枪
In China, no one shoots in wall.
在中国 没人手上有枪
In China, no one has gun.
在我签约之前
Before I sign up for anything,
我们来谈谈"价码面议"这部分
talk to me about that, "salary negotiable" part.
你喜欢银块吗？凯力先生
Do you like silver, Mr. Kelly?
当然喜欢了
I reckon I do.
等到怪物通通解决了
Well, then, upon dispatching all the aforementioned creatures,
而且矿坑可以开工了 我会用银块付给你
and upon the subsequent re-opening of the mine, you'll be paid in silver,
多得让你用马匹也载不动
say as much as you can carry on a strong horse.
我相信
Well, now, I just bet that you could
重赏之下必有勇夫
charm a cow right out of her calf
一定叫人难以拒绝
with those fancy words.
但是为了我自己 我得先收点订金
But now, for myself, I sort of need a little something up front.
我们身上可没有钱
Well, we don't have any money.
那好
Ah, Well.
谢谢你们花时闲陪我
Thank you for your time.
我有钱
Double Eagle.
这是订金
A down payment.
告诉你
Tell you what.
只要你给我袖扣
You throw in them there cufflinks,
这件事就搞定了
and you got yourself a deal.
你收集的枪
This is one sorry collection
真是可悲啊
of lead pushers you got here.
我的店是不卖枪的 凯力先生
I'm not running a gun store, Mr. Kelly.
这把长枪给你用
Juan, you take this here, big old .45-70.
你自己挑一把枪吧
Hiram, pick yourself out something
要合适的
that feels right in your hand.
把你所有的子弹都给我们
And, you give us all these blue whistlers that you got.
- 哇噢 - 胡安
- Whoa. - Juan!
这给你
Take this.
我还是付不起
Oh, but, Lu Wan, I still can't afford it, no.
不必付钱 送给你
No credit, it's a gift.
谢谢
Gracias.
怎么？在中国人人头上都戴着帽子
What? No one goes without a hat in China.
我们浩浩荡荡出发吧
Okay, boys, let's jingle some spurs.
不 不要张扬
No. No. No spurs.
不要发出任何的声响
In fact, no jingling of any kind.
那些怪物只要听到 一点声音就会过来
I tell you, these things are attracted by the slightest noise.
而且随时会从地底窜出来
They could leap from the ground at any moment.
胡安在这里杀了一只
Juan killed one right here.
这里也什么也没有
There ain't nothing here neither.
可能它们都聋了
Maybe they gone deaf.
还是你们 这两个家伙在耍我
Or maybe you two boys are playing me for the fool.
我付你钱是假的吗？
After what I paid you?
我们必须不断的搜查
We will just have to keep looking.
拜托你 帮我一把
Juan, if you please, some help.
少来了 你丢不丢脸？
Gummer, dag nab it, ain't you got no pride?
自己想法子上马去
Get up on the horse by yourself!
我若需要重新学学骑术
Should I ever again require horsemanship,
我会找个老师教我的
I will engage a tutor.
告诉你
Well, I'll tell you one thing.
虽然我没读过什么书 但是我很清楚
I ain't got your book-learning but I know this,
长大成人 不代表你就是个男人
being full-growed don't make you a man.
看
Look, look, look, look.
这里
Here, here
好像是蛋壳 是蛋
They appear to be shells. Eggs.
若这是它们的蛋…
Well, if that's what they are,
那一定是只很大的母鸡生下的
then they came out of one big chicken.
或许你们俩 真的不是胡言乱语
Or maybe you two aren't as crazy as I've been thinking.
这是我们从矿坑 引出来的温泉
This is where we pipe the hot spring from the mine.
水从土中穿过 看到没？
The water cut through the dirt, you see?
所以蛋露出来了
And the eggs fell out.
可能是温泉让它们孵化的
Perhaps the warm water hatched them?
这样就知道有几只了
Juan, this tells us how many there are.
有四只 一只已经被我干掉了
There are four. And I killed one already.
剩下三只
Three left.
但是它们会在哪里呢？
But where could they have gone?
我们继续骑马去找吧
Well, we're just going to keep on riding until we find them,
我想要马上就好好地
because I'm getting awful anxious
大干一票
to unravel me some cartridges.
这温泉是六个月前引出来的
You know, we piped that hot water out only six months ago.
这些怪物长大得真快
Then, those creatures grew large quite quickly.
那是其中一只的一部分
That's a part of one of them.
它们背上有这种鳞片
These scaly things were on their backs.
是的
Yeah.
可能其中有一只死掉了
Well, maybe one of them there "things" died.
或者那只是脱皮 就像蛇一样
Or maybe... Maybe he shed his skin, like a snake.
谁在那里？
Who is that?
是老费迪 那是他的马车
It's Old Fred. At least, that's his wagon.
老天哪
Good Lord.
我有不好的预感
This does not bode well.
只剩下支离破碎的残骸了
Now that is one catawampusly chawed-up rig.
我就说过…
As I keep saying... saying.
这种东西可不是好对付的
These things are not to be trifled with.
老费迪？
Old Fred?
我觉得应该要弄长一点
Maybe we should have made it longer.
我不要再搬石头了
Well, I'm not toting no more rocks.
我们应该说些告别词
We should say something.
我根本就不认识他
I didn't even know the man.
拿下你的帽子
Take off your hat.
费迪是个老人
Fred was an old man.
所以我们才叫他老费迪
That is why we call him Old Fred.
他负责运货
He drove the freight.
他有口臭 只是我不讲而已
He had bad breath. But I don't want to say that.
好了
All right. All right.
"无惧炎炎的热日
"Fear no more the heat of the sun.
也无畏刺骨的冬寒
Nor the furious winter's rages.
直到你的使命完成了
Thou thy worldly task hast done.
回归家园 丰硕一生"
Home art gone, and ta'en thy wages."
这是辛白林第四幕的第二场戏 我们该走了
Cymbeline. Act IV, Scene 2. We'd best get going.
等一下 我们在这里扎营吧
Uh, wait, Let's make camp here.
不 我们要到山岭上
No, no. We'll go to the ridge.
要在石地上扎营
Camp on solid rock.
就如每个晚上一样
As we have every night.
那还要走三英里路 路很不好走
No, no, that is three miles back there. That's hard country.
难道要我冒险 睡在这毫无防护的地面上…
If you think I'm going to risk sleeping on the naked earth...
我们可以到驿站去
Or we could go down to the muling station.
就在峡谷那里
Down the canyon.
安全吗？
Is it safe?
当然了
Yes, there are very thick beams
那里地上铺着排列马车的板子
on the floor, you know, for the wagons.
土龙没办法窜出来的
There is no way these dragons could break through them.
那里会有人在吗？
Might there be someone here?
没有 补给的马车不来了…
No, they stopped running the supply wagons, now that the...
矿坑关闭了
Now that the mine is closed.
我的生命只剩下苦头可吃
Yes, the bitter refrain of my life, it seems.
我们得把马绑好
We must secure these horses with certainty.
上次马匹跑掉了 真糟糕
The last time, they got away.
你要确保 大门是牢牢的关上
You just make sure that gate is tied up tight.
凯力
Mr. Kelly.
你面对这一边 根本就看不到大门
You can't see the door if you're facing this direction.
随时保持警戒
Always be prepared.
这是什么鬼东西？
What in God's name?
就是这些鬼东西吗？
So, was that them?
不是
No! No!
是另一种东西
Something new.
是你要我挑一把顺手的枪
You said to pick something I was comfortable with.
没错 是我说的
You're right. I did say that.
怎么有这种怪味道？
What in Sam Hill is that smell?
它们来了 就是这味道
It's them. That's the smell.
记得吧 先生
Remember, sefior?
但是它们变了 变得更长更细
But they've changed so, become long and thin.
一共有六只 可能有九只
There's six of them or even nine.
最好把马匹带进来
We'd better bring the horses inside.
马儿又不见了
Chingada! They're gone. Again!
我们不能靠自己跑
We can't go on foot.
一定会被捉住的
They'll get us for sure.
好吧
All right.
那我们就在这里不动
All right, that means we have to stand our ground here.
现在你得真的学会用枪了
Hiram, it's about time you learned how to use a real piece.
那是你的工作 我要找人用枪 所以我雇用你
That's your job. If I need a gun fired, I hire a gunman.
你若想带着美女上床
If you want to bed down with a real pretty woman,
难道你也会雇人来做吗？
I suppose you just hire somebody to do that, too.
不必在这里耍嘴皮子
Spare me your tiresome analogies.
好 我说过一遍了 现在我再说一次
Hiram! Now I said this once, and I'm gonna say it one more time.
有些事情是要亲力而为的
There's some things that a man has to do for himself,
现在这件事就是要靠自己
and right now shooting is one of them.
把那笨东西给我
And give me that stupid hideout piece.
这对你根本没有用
It ain't gonna do you no good now.
好了 胡安
Okay, Juan.
你好好注意 那些蛇样的鬼东西
You keep your eye peeled for them there snake things.
注意
Pay attention, Hiram.
我要用左轮手枪了
Now, this is a single-action Colt Army.
这是最好的左轮手枪
This is the finest wheel gun ever made.
不要笨手笨脚的握枪
Don't be holding it like it's some skunk.
那是你手掌的延伸
Now, it's an extension of your hand, okay?
是你身体的一部分
Hmm. It's part of you.
就位瞄准 好好发狠
And take yourself a stance, like you mean it.
怎么发狠？
Mean what? Like you mean
你手上的枪管
that every last lead plum,
所发出的每一发子弹 都是快狠准的击中目标
that comes out of that barrel is gonna kill whatever you aim at.
对 对 打一枪
Okay, okay, take yourself a shot
对着窗子上的罐子
at that can over there by the window.
你伸直手臂对准目标
You line up this blade with this notch.
然后扣下板机
Then you just squeeze the trigger.
不要猛按
You don't jerk it.
噢
Oh!
没关系
It's all right.
它们没法子窜过地上的板子
They cannot break through the floor beams.
好 放轻松
Now you just relax.
把眼睛
You just let your eyes,
脑子 手掌和手指
your brain, your hand, your trigger finger, okay?
都合而为一
All becomes one.
没关系 现在你控制得很好
It's all right. You got consistency now.
这真是浪费时闲
This is a waste of time!
那你还想怎么样？
What do you expect?
难道你以为花20分钟 就可以学会我20年的工夫吗？
You wanna learn in 20 minutes what took me 20 years?
它们没法子穿过地板
They cannot break through the floor,
所以就想要把地板拆开
so they are tearing it apart.
哪里来这种大蛇呢？
How could a snake be so strong?
看那里 它们在设陷阱
Look at that! They decoyed us!
老天 它们怎么这么聪明？
Good Lord! How smart are they?
我们快要没有立足之地了
Esta malo, we're gonna have nothing left to stand on.
电报呢？
A telegraph?
没啥好用处
Yes, but it's no good for us.
我们根本不知道怎么打
We don't know the clicking code.
随便打点东西
Well, click anything!
就有人会知道
Surely someone will hear us.
不知是什么 那不是摩斯码
I don't know what it means. It's not in Morse code.
已经持续了一个小时了吗？
This has been going on for more than an hour?
或许是树枝碰到电线 以前也曾经这样子
Maybe a tree is touching the wire. That happened before.
这个不一样
No. This is different.
卡森城的电报员
But surely, the telegrapher from Carson City
不会让这种事发生的
wouldn't allow such foolishness with his equipment.
可能不是来自卡森城
Maybe not Carson City.
不是那里 还会有哪里？
Not Carson City? Where else?
这才是来自卡森城的
This is from Carson City.
那个是哪儿来的？
Where's that one from?
来自驿站的 一定是甘先生
This is from the muling station. It must be Mr. Gummer.
只有他会在那里
He's the only one out there.
迪科帕和阿彭几时会回来？
When did Tecopa and Pyong say that they'd be back?
一两天吧 他们出城去了 去买柴火
One, two days. Gone up-country. Getting firewood.
好吧 那我自己去
All right then. I'll go myself.
嗯？
Eh?
你一定要打得这么用力吗？
Must you tap so loudly?
你只管用枪就好
Let your lead fly, man!
到底要对付的 是什么鬼东西？
What the hell are we up against?
它们长大了
They grew.
那些根本不是蛇 那是舌头
Those snakes are not snakes. They are tongues.
三个舌头
Three tongues!
每只怪物有三个舌头
Each creature has three tongues.
我们看到了九个舌头
And we saw nine before.
所以一共只有三只怪物
So, there's still only three animals.
这值得我高兴吗？
And that's supposed to make me feel better?
每只怪物都比 配八只驴子的货运马车还要大
Good God, man, those things are the size of eight-mule freight wagons!
快开枪 那是你的工作
Well, shoot them! That's what you're hired to do!
我们要先清楚对手
You got to know your enemy, Hiram!
我应该要带大炮来的
I ought to be totingsome eight-bore firing solid shot.
至少也要有火炮枪 而不是手上这种小玩意
Or some damn punt gun. Not these weapons I got.
好了 告诉你我们该怎么做
All right. All right. I'll tell you what we're gonna do.
我们先不要开枪 等到它们追了过来
We're gonna hold our fire till they come after us.
然后我们一股作气
And then we're gonna gotoe-to-toe,
全力攻击扫射一番 用所有的子弹打它们
point-blank, full-bore, throw all the lead we got at 'em!
然后看看是否有幸运中奖的
And then, maybe we'll get a lucky hit.
说不定一枪命中什么的
A brain shot. Or something!
地板剩下没几片了
There is not much floor left.
它们随时要展开攻击了
They'll be makingtheir move any time.
准备好
Get ready.
或许就是这次了
This may be it.
它们在打什么主意？
Now what are they up to?
凯力
Mr. Kelly!
吃子弹吧
Eat this!
我没子弹了
I'm out! I'm out!
克莉斯丁来了
Christine is coming, SenorGummer!
在这里
Christine! Over here!
驾着马车快跑
Just drive the wagon!
凯力先生在哪里？
Where's Mr. Kelly?
死了 快走 快
Dead! Go!Go!Go!
干得好
Well done, Mrs. Lord!
它们有跟上来吗？
Are they following us?
不知道
I can't tell!
有 它们在后面
Yes! They are following us!
快一点
Faster!
- 它们已经到了极限 - 快点
- They're at their limit! - Come on!
走着瞧吧
We shall see!
它们好大 穷凶恶极
They're enormous. Ravenous.
"来自暗处中的兽精"
Spirit demons from dark places,
"吞噬了光明中的灵魂"
eating souls that live in the light.
这是我们的传说
Part of our legend.
我们不断对它们开枪
We put bullet after bullet into them
却一点也阻档不了它们
and it didn't even slow them down.
它们会追过来吗？到镇上吗？
Will they come here, to our town?
那它们得通过障碍
They have to get through the pass from the upper valley.
有许多石头 应该过不来吧
Lots of rocks. Maybe they can not do it.
那不重要 矿坑还是无法接近
It hardly matters. The mine will remain unapproachable.
那你有什么打算？
So what is your intention?
我的打算是离开这邪恶之地
My intention? To leave this godforsaken place,
你们也应该快走
as should all of you!
可是那矿坑…
But the mine.
你听懂没？矿坑没有了 忘掉一切吧
Are you listening? The mine is lost! Forget the mine.
重新开始你的生活吧
Go on with your lives as if it never existed.
一切重新开始 我也是一样
Start your lives over, just as I will have to.
我才不会让这种笨虫 逼得离开自己的土地
No stupid animal is going to make me leave my land.
我要到卡森城去 我要买些火药
I can go to Carson City, get some blasting powder.
我们已经走运了 真的走运
Juan,one we were lucky. Dumb lucky.
像黑手凯力这种好手都完蛋了
If a man like Black Hand Kelly is no match for them,
我们还有什么机会呢？
what chance do we have?
留下来做什么？
Pyong, why in heaven would you stay?
带着福元和老婆回中国去吧
Take Fu Yien and the missis back to China.
我老婆不走
Lu Wan forgets.
中国不完美 世上没有完美之处
China not perfect. No place perfect.
我们不要离开新的家园
We will not leave our new home.
我会找人来拿我的东西
I shall send for my belongings.
当然 马匹和设备我会送回来
And, of course, I shall see to it that the horse and equipment are returned.
那倒不必
That won't be necessary.
马儿就给你吧
You can keep the horse and the saddle
还有这马鞍 来福枪 还有小刀
and the rifle and the knife.
和你交换那矿坑所有权
In trade for ownership of the mine.
你不是开玩笑吧
You can't be serious.
这是你能得到最好的条件了
It's the best offer you're going to get.
等我回到费城 最低要以五万美元出售矿坑
When I reach Philadelphia, I intend to sell that mine for at least $50,000.
在那之前我会先用电报 发送新闻消息
You will be preceded by a telegram to the newspapers,
告诉大家怪物的事
describing in great detail these creatures that plague the mine,
还有不能采矿的事
and why it is unworkable.
你们不会这样出卖我的
That's blackmail. You wouldn't betray me like that.
我们投票通过了
We voted.
四比一通过赞成
Four-to-one in favor of doing exactly that.
至少剩下一个人有道德感
At least one of you has some sense of ethics.
我投的是把你推下悬崖
I voted to drop you off a cliff.
留下来 一起战斗吧
Stay with us, Hiram. Stay and fight.
你们在浪费生命
You're wasting your lives.
那邪恶矿坑给你们
You can have the cursed mine!
喔噢
Whoa! Whoa!
请不要离开我们
Mr. Gummer. Please don't leave us.
我帮不上忙
Fu Yien, I can't help you.
我们错了 它们来了
We were wrong. They're coming.
那些土龙通过了山谷的障碍
The dirt dragons. They got through the upper valley pass.
还不知几时会到 就快过来了
I don't know when, but they are definitely coming.
或许它们不发现我们 直往南去
Maybe they not find us. Keep going south.
它们会听声音
No,no,no,no, they hunt by sound.
在这里只有我们会出声音
We are the only thing making noise between here and Carson City.
签上说的是什么？
What do the sticks say?
"穷凶恶极即将降临"
"Expect a ferocious arrival."
那就完了
Well, this is it then.
摒弃镇完蛋了
The end of Rejection.
(车站)
一张下一班到费城的车票
One ticket for your next train to Philadelphia.
要有卧铺的 单程
Sleeping car, one way.
好的
Yes, sir.
傻瓜
Fools!
你再说一遍
I beg your pardon?
摒弃镇那些人
The people up in Rejection.
真是天大的玩笑
Funnier than a dancing bear, eh?
这是昨天送过来的
Here's one they sent yesterday.
"巨虫通过山谷 可能到达城镇"
"Giant worms have left upper valley. May find town."
可以借我吗？
May I?
"即刻需要救助"
"Need immediate help."
"有巨虫"
"Giant worms."
一张票
One ticket...
先生 你的票
Sir? Your ticket?
(理查火药枪弹之家)
我想做个拉车
I was thinkingmaybe I could make some kind of sled for it,
可以用马车来拉
and we could pull it behind the last wagon.
来不及了
There's no room.
还是放弃吧
Time to let it go.
你要去哪里呢？
Juan, where will you go?
听说多诺帕有个新的矿坑
Well, there is a new strike, down near Tonopah.
我想到那里去
I'm thinking of heading that way.
那我们要去哪里呢？
Where will we go?
我们到三藩市去
We are going to San Francisco.
然后回去中国
And then back to China.
我们的钱都投在店里 现在全都没有了
All our money is put in the store, and now it's all gone.
你不能像爸爸妈妈一样 在铁路上工作
And you are not going to work on the rail road like Momma and Poppa.
它们来了
They're coming!
不 等一下
No,no,no. Wait, wait, wait.
它们是从北边过来的 不是从南边
They will come from the north, not from the south.
那是别的东西 或是另有其人
That is something else. Or someone.
哪个可怜的家伙 挑这个时候来这里的呢？
What poor soul would be coming here now?
是甘先生
It's Mr. Gummer!
快点
Come on! Whoa!
"穷凶恶极即将降临"吗？
"A ferocious arrival"?
嗨
Hyah!
或许我最后会让你留下他
Well, now, maybe I'll let you keep him after all.
停下 哎呀 真是的
Whoa! Stop! Whoa! Curse you!
不轻易妥协的野兽
Whoa! You intransigent beasts!
看到你们安好无恙真好
Delighted to see you're all well.
它们随时就会到达了
Hiram, they're coming. They could be here at any minute!
- 我知道 - 你到底在想什么？
- I know. - Whatever are you thinking?
这西部田园不该
That this idyllic Western retreat
让那些没脑子的怪物霸占
shall not fall prey to these mindless predators.
我带了很多武器
I have here a cache of weapons
连已故黑手凯力看了都会笑
that would impress even the late Black Hand Kelly.
这是52口径的来福猎枪
One Sharps .52 caliber buffalo rifle.
这是45口径的长枪
One Remington .45-120, Rolling block.
这是猎枪
One Henry repeater rifle.
口径虽小 火力可不小
Smaller caliber, but impressive rate of fire.
还有八发子弹…
One 8-gauge Remington, uh...
德林加枪
Derringer.
这是新型的长枪
One LC Smith 10-gauge stub-twist coach gun.
还有这个
And this!
火炮枪
A two-inch bore punt gun!
你怎么会有这些东西？你不是没有钱了吗？
Hiram, how did you get all of these things? You don't have any money.
有个智者曾告诉我
A wise friend once told me it's not important
重要的不是我怎么花钱 而是我怎么运用生命
how you spend your money, but how you spend your life.
你觉得我们应该怎么办呢？
Hiram Gummer, what is it you think we are going to do? Hmm?
夫人 我们要给这些访客
Madam, I intend we throw our visitors
来个出其不意的反击
a little corpse and cartridge occasion.
我们要这样面对面 和那些可恶的怪物打斗
That we stand our ground and fight these despicable beasts to the death!
我们要战斗
We will fight!
对
Right!
我花了两年才说服你 离开中国
It takes me two years to make you leave China.
我才不想再回去
You think I want to go back?
- 我们愿意 - 把它们都踩扁
- We do it. - We'll stomp 'em like snakes.
烧个精光
We will burn them down.
一只只捉来活烤
We'll smoke 'em up!
我了解你
Ah! Juan, knowing you,
你需要新帽子
you'll need a spare.
谢谢
Gracias, amigo.
它们应该会从北边 或东北边过来
They'll probably be coming from the north or the northeast.
然后我们跳出去扫射它们
Then we go out there and shoot them.
那太危险
Too dangerous!
它们可能来自四面八方
They can come up anywhere.
我们可不能 赤手空拳引诱它们
Yes. We dare not face them on their terms.
用马 它们一过来…
We should take a horse out there and when they go for it...
太残酷了
Tecopa, that's cruel!
我们正处在残酷的时刻
Well, these are cruel times!
难道不能用别的东西 来发出声音吗？
Can't we make noise with something else?
好主意
That is a good idea, Fu-ito.
只要有声音就可以
Any noise works,
不见得要用马匹
itdoesn% have to be a horse.
我们可以弄出这样的声音
We could make noise on something like this,
只要它们出现 我们就开枪
and then when they come up, we shoot them.
对 来个愉袭
Yes, an ambush.
把它们引到枪口来
We will lead them into our very gun-muzzles.
摒弃镇就是我们的要塞 最后一道防线
We will make Rejection our last bastion, our last line of defense!
我们的阿拉莫
Our Alamo!
阿拉莫是战败的地方
Juan, we were the losers at the Alamo.
你自己才失败 乡巴佬
Speak for yourself, gringo.
还要罐头 需要更多铁罐
More cans. I need more cans.
我已经尽快在吃了
I'm eating as fast as I can.
你这是干什么？
What is all this?
我们要怎么知道它们来了？又看不见它们
When they come, how do we know they come? We cannot see them.
这是个问题
Well, that is a concern.
只要地面在晃动
When the ground shakes...
我们就会知道了
...we know they are here.
好办法
Dandy.
火炮枪是什么东西？
What is a punt gun?
那是猎鸭用的 可以打很多鸭子
It has something to do with shooting ducks. A great many ducks.
"给它上足了火药 火力十足好好冲刺"
"Pour in one pound of shot or balls. Ram it down tight."
我们不需要马匹吗？
Won't we need the horses?
万一我们打不过的话
I mean, if we lose the fight?
不能让马出声音 否则我们的陷阱会失败
Can't have them making unnecessary noise. Might spoil our trap.
而且我们不会打不过
And we're not going to lose, Fu-ito.
开始了吧
Shall we begin?
或许明天该再试试看
Maybe we should try again tomorrow.
阿彭可能是对的
Perhaps Pyong was right.
或许它们已经前往卡森城去了
Perhaps they've bypassed us for Carson City.
我不知道
I don't know.
山谷南端的山岭上都是石块 就像一道墙一样
The ridge at the south end of the valley is all rock, like a big wall.
我不认为它们会过得来
I don't think they can get past it.
它们一定还躲在某个地方
They gotta be somewhere.
不 福
No! Fu!
快回去吧
Get inside!
可是我也想战斗
But I wanna fight, too!
福
Fu, Fu.
这店是我们的要塞
The store is our fort.
要塞不能没有人看守
We can't ever leave the fort unguarded.
你留守在里面
You stay inside and keep guard.
就是现在
NOW!
你打歪了 那是大炮耶
You missed! With a cannon!
上哪儿去了？
Where did it go?
或许被炮声吓走了
Maybe the noise scared him away.
又回来了
Mr. Gummer, it's coming! It's coming back!
快点
Hiram, quick!
好
Yeah!
成功了
It worked!
臭毙了
It stinks!
- 那边 - 还有两只
- There! - Two more to go.
赶快就位 退到里面
Take your positions! Fu Yien, back inside!
胡安
Juan!
它会是故意的吗？
Did it do that on purpose?
当心
Juan, look out!
嗯？
Huh?
没办法打穿泥地
Cannot shoot through dirt.
过来呀 可恶的怪物
Come on, you son of a bitch!
噢 天哪 迪科帕 谢谢
Ay caramba. Tecopa, gracias.
太神奇了
Astonish...
太聪明了 我的天哪
Astonishingly clever, my man.
它抢你的炮 它会知道吗？
It take your gun. Did it know?
我看它们聪明绝顶
I fear they are very intelligent.
但还是不如我们
But not as smart as us.
对 是不如我们聪明 只剩下一只了
No. Not as smart as us. There's only one left.
它躲到哪里去了 让它自己跑出来
Now, where the hell is it? Let it show itself.
迪科帕
Tecopa.
它走了吗？
Is it leaving?
不会的 它在绕圈子 听声音
No. No, it's circling, listening.
找猎物在哪里
For Prey
那我们怎么办？
What do we do?
看来我们的来福枪 没有办法把它干掉
It seems like our rifles aren't strong enough to kill it.
没有火炮枪 我看我们输定了
Without the punt gun, I feel we're lost.
我们不打了吗？要放弃吗？
So, we just stop the fight, then? Give up?
或许该发动拖车 想办法离开
Maybe we take traction engine. Try to get away.
车移动得很慢
It moves so slowly.
你要离开这镇上吗？
And you would leave our town?
有其他办法杀掉它吗？
You have ideas for killing it?
人可以学习面对一切难关
A man must learn to sail in all winds.
我们手上有什么 就要用什么
We must do what we can with what we have.
讲得真好
Well said.
你有火药
You have black powder.
要不要想法子引爆
Maybe we could blow it up somehow.
当然 我们来放大炮
Sure! We make big firecracker.
- 这个我懂 - 太好了
- I know how. - Excellent!
但要静静的
But quietly.
慢慢走
Move very, very slowly.
你去里面拿麻绳当引线
Fu Yien, you go inside and get twine for fuse.
好的
Okay.
你在做什么？
What are you doing?
这种火药必须很细
The powder for the fuse must be very fine.
快要好了 只要再几分钟
Almost there. Just another few minutes.
福
Fu!
我看不到门
I can't see the door!
你要保持安静
Fu, Fu, stay very quiet.
现在出声音
Make noise!
在外面
Out here!
嘿
Hey!
它怎么不追我们 它听到声音吗？
Why doesn't it come for us? For the noise?
不知道 它也在学习进步
I don't know! They keep learning our every trick!
就在这里
Mama. He's over here!
就是它了 好小子
Go on. That's it, boy. Good boy!
快跑
Run, run!
赶快 上马车
Hurry up. For the wagon! To the wagon!
上去
Get on!
老天哪
Oh, good Lord!
去拿来福枪
Let's get the rifles!
炸弹
The bomb!
你要把炸弹做好
Pyong, you must finish the bomb!
- 我还需要一点时闻 - 快点
- I need more time! - Hurry!
根本就没有时闲完成
We'll never have time to finish that!
我有个点子
I have an idea!
那大条带子
Pyong, that big belt!
太好了
Excellent! Excellent!
来帮个手
Tecopa! Help us here!
我们需要找个勾子
All we need is some kind of hook!
我知道在哪里
I know where.
就在这里
Over here, Juan!
去
Go!
小心
Oh, watch out!
好了
Good
你还好吧？
Mrs. Lord, are you well?
还好 你呢？
All right. Are you all right?
是的 我很好
Well, yes, lam.
迪科帕？
Tecopa?
噢 谢天谢地
Ay, gracias, amiguito.
你成功了
You got 'em, Mr. Gummer.
对 你成功了
Yes, Hiram. You got 'em.
不
No, no.
是我们成功了
We got 'em.
干得好
Well job.
银行批准你的贷款
Hiram, the bank has approved your loan.
你可以重新雇人 重开矿坑
You can hire new workers. Reopen the mine.
要是我没记错 那已不是我的
Well, if I recall, it no longer belongs to me.
那是你的 是你的矿坑
It's yours, Hiram. It's your mine.
我们不能欺骗你
We couldn't cheat you that way.
你比我们还要需要那矿坑
You need it worse than we do.
你们真好
That's very kind of you.
但我有两个条件
But I'll only assume ownership under two conditions.
条件？
Conditions?
我们绝对不告诉任何人 有关土龙的事
We agree never to tell anyone about the dirt dragons.
要是这种事传出去 没有人再敢来这里的
If word of them ever got out, no one would ever settle here.
第二个条件呢？
And the second condition?
我的第一笔收入 将会用来建造有真正围墙的
That the first proceeds of the mine are used to build a hotel,
旅馆和店铺
and a market with real walls.
并且帮胡安买地 还有…
To pay off Juan's land, and,uh.
你想要什么？
Tecopa, what do you what?
新的雕像 看起来要像我的样子
A new statue. One that looks like me.
还要为迪科帕作个雕像
And to commission a statue for Tecopa.
大家都同意吗？
Is everyone agreed to this?
(完美城)
我被你们同化了
I am fearfully out-classed.
你能够留下来真好
It's good you've decided to stay.
只要我学会矿坑经营技巧
I shall personally supervise the mine.
我就会自己来管理一切
I mean, as soon as I learn how it all works.
而且我会物色一个 很棒的地方当作我的家
And uh, I've selected an excellent location for my home.
要在高地上 完整的防护
On high ground. Readily defended.
甚至要建造个地下室
It will even have a basement.
那房子一个人住太大了
That's an awful lot of room for one person.
理想中
Ideally,
不会只有一个人住
it won't be for just one.
我真是无药可救
Oh, I really am hopeless.
多做练习你就会进步的
You'll get better with a little practice.
与此同时
In the meantime,
我买了个东西 可以帮助你瞄准
I purchased something that might aid in your success as a marksman.
好棒
Oh. Dandy.
哈兰
Hiram.
嗯…
Um...
嗯哼
Uh-huh.